

4/3/h/46, Bhukailash Road, Kolkata-700023, West Bengal, INDIA

🛮 (+91) 7799126262 / 9883917741 | 💌 abhishekjaiswal.kol@gmail.com | 🏕 jabhishek87.github.io/ | 🖸 jabhishek87 | 🖼 jabhishek87 | 💆 @jabhishek87

### Summary\_

12+ years experience specializing in backend/infrastructure, web development and computer security. Super nerd who loves Sublime, Vim, Linux and OS X and enjoys to customize all of the development environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

7+ years of experience in Openstack support and writing infrastructure as a code using ansible and python, technically sound with Containers, kubernetes (Kubernetes certified Administrator), Jenkins and devops technologies

3+ years experience specializing kubernetes, kubernetes Certified [CKA/CKAD]

### Ski**lls**

Thorough knowledge of Python, Ansible, Javascript, PHP, Openstack, Terraform

adept at frameworks like django, webpy, flask

**Technically sound with** Linux, Networking, Kubernetes, Docker Adept with tools and utilities like Pycharm, Sublime, Vim, Eclipse, Iterm,

Adroit with source code management using GIT. SVN. Gerrit. Jenkins High potential to utilize scripting languages HTML, XML, YAML

**Proficient in Operating Sytem like** Windows xp/7/8, Ubuntu, OSX

# Work Experience \_

Ericsson India Kolkata, West Bengal, INDIA

SOLUTIONS ARCHITECT [PYTHON/DEVOPS/TESTING] Sep, 2018 - PRESENT

- Working on different projects on NFVI, Openstack, Kubernetes
- Implemented Sonobuoy Testing Framework with additional capabilities using python unittests.
- · worked on AQUA Frameworks.
- Working as a lead Contributer for a major American telco operator's cloud platform
- · Worked on several POC projects in Docker, Kubernetes, ansible, focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance, and auto-scaling.

**Teradata Labs** Hyderabad, Telangana, INDIA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER III [PYTHON/DEVOPS]

- Implemented python based web app to cater different needs.
- Implemented ELK Automation on ansible to add n host for monitoring.
- Worked on writing Vagrant files for different application
- · Worked on several POC projects in Docker, Kubernetes, ansible, focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance, and auto-scaling.

#### **Pramati Technologies** Hyderabad, Telangana, INDIA

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER [PYTHON]

Apr, 2015 - Mar, 2018

- Core member of AIC Development Team OpsSimple. · Adequate Knowledge of Miranis Fuel
- Supported Different faloyours of AIC deployment.

• Worked on several Odoo (formerly openerp) projects.

- Implemented djangorestframework RESTful API server for internal projects.
- Implemented Data driven Framework in python/djangorestframework frontend/backend.
- · Worked on Automation Framework in Ansible to deploy Openstack for one of the largest Telecom Provider.
- Worked on several POC projects in Docker, Kubernetes, ansible, focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance, and auto-scaling.
- Developed an easy-to-use Payment module which connects to major PG(Payment Gateway).

#### **MindFire Solutions** Bhubaneswar, Orrisa, INDIA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER [PYTHON]

Nov. 2012 - Apr. 2015

Apr, 2018 - Sep, 2018

- Worked on Customized ERP Application for Custom Brokerage and warehousing using odoo framework in python.
- Worked on Web based ERP Solutions for Importers and Exporters using PHP, EXTjs, Mysql.

#### Acumen Consultancy PvtLtd

Kolkata, WestBengal, INDIA

WEB ENGINEER [PHP]

Jun, 2010 - Nov. 2012

- Worked on IMS-Pharmastat, web based CMS using PHP (Codeigniter), Javascript, Mysql. (http://imspharmastat.fr/)
- · Worked on UBI-France, Web Based Doctor Directory Listing using PHP (Codeigniter), Javascript, Mysql.
- Worked on Open2leads, Question and Answer Forum for B2B with social-networking features, Using PHP (symfony), JavaScript, MySQL.

### Education

#### **Institute Of Engineering & management**

MASTER OF COMPUTER APPLICATION (MCA)

Kolkata, WestBengal, INDIA

• Major in Computer Applications

#### Acharya Institute of Management & Sciences, Bangalore University,

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER APPLICATION (BCA)

Major in Computer Applications

### WBCHSE, (West Bengal Council of Higher Secondary Education)

HIGHER SECONDARY, PUC

· Accounts Major

Bangalore, Karnatka, INDIA

2006 - 2009

Kolkata, WestBengal, INDIA

2004 - 2006

# Projects\_

### NC (AT&T Network Cloud) Automation Team

Tech Stack: Python, Bandit, Tempest, Kubernetes, Sonobuoy, Openstack, Jenkins

Role: Understanding the requirement of different internal teams and providing solution under Automation Framework.

Leading Team for Infra Testing (UAT, ORT, PVT)

Implement Proper User Access Management using AT&T's own tool called UAM.

Design frameworks for executing different tests scope such as Tempest, Sonobuoy,..etc

### AIC (AT&T Integrated Cloud) Security Scrum

Tech Stack: Ansible, Python, Bandit, Pentest, Sensage, Foreman, OWASP, MetaSploit

Role: Analysis and Scope Various Security related vulnerabilities in the Platform.

Some of them are SSL related vulnerabilities (week ssl cipher).

Implement Proper User Access Management using AT&T's own tool called UAM.

perform series of checks for known/reported vulnerabilities such as Meltdown and Spectre, shellshock, DNS Bind server vulnerabilities etc

#### **WebApp for Automation Support**

Tech Stack: Python, Django, PGSQL, AngularJS, Ansible, Shell, Docker,

Python Django Web based Application

Data gatehering tool for large scale Openstack Deployment

handled various security related vulnerabilities like Cross site scripting (XSS) protection,

Cross site request forgery (CSRF) protection, SQL injection protection Clickjacking protection,

Host header validation, Session security

### **Shipment Module for Openerp**

python, Openerp, PGSQL

Online Customized ERP Application for Importers and Exporters

Team Lead, Database, code reviews, test plan and test case Deployment, Maintenance

# **Achievements**

2022	Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals.	Certificate ID No: l123-6934
------	---	------------------------------

<sup>2021</sup> Certified Kubernetes Application Developer, Certificate ID No: LF-54hmw0vvsp

2020 Certified Kubernetes Administrator, Certificate ID No: LF-x136iapa4c

# RED HAT CERTIFIED SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR IN RED HAT OPENSTACK,

https://www.redhat.com/rhtapps/certification/verify/?certId=160-236-972

2017 Learn DevOps: The Complete Kubernetes, https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-L2FLIMPW/

2012 **Zend Certified Php5 Developer**, ClientCandidateID=ZEND023657

2012 Microsoft Certified Developer, Microsoft Certification ID: 9784595

2012 certified in ERP-Essential (Microsoft Dynamics),

2010 Runner up Embedding System Programming inter-college held in IEM post-graduate level,

2007 College Festival Organizer,

2007 Undergraduate level College Festival organizer,